schoolrunner.org 2017-06-06

# Schoolrunner | Privacy Policy

Schoolrunner Inc., a Denver corporation ("Schoolrunner") is the owner and operator of the websites www.schoolrunner.org, and such other URLs as may be designated in the future (the "Websites"). Schoolrunner is committed to protecting the online privacy of visitors to the Websites. The privacy policy set forth below (this "Policy") applies only to the Websites and online services provided by Schoolrunner. The purpose of this Policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you when you visit our Websites, how we may use that information, and how we may disclose it to third parties. This Policy also covers our treatment of any information about you that our third-party business partners share with us or that we share with our third-party business partners. This Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that we do not own or control, including but not limited to any third party websites, services and applications ("Third Party Services") that you elect to access through the Websites or to individuals that we do not manage or employ. While we attempt to enable access only to those Third Party Services that share our respect for your privacy, we cannot take responsibility for the content or privacy policies of those Third Party Services. Please make sure to review the privacy policies of any Third Party Services you access.

BY USING THE WEBSITES, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THESE TERMS, PLEASE DO NOT USE THE WEBSITES.

1\. Information That We Collect

A. Personal Information – At various locations on the Websites, such as in registration forms, surveys, and polls, we may request that you supply us with "personal information" consisting of your name, telephone number, address, and credit card details. We use your personal information to, among other things, send you updates, news and promotional offers. You may choose not to receive updates, news and/or promotional offers of this type by updating the notification settings of your account. If you do choose to give us personal information through the Websites, we will collect and retain that information.

B. Non-Personal Information – When you use the Websites, we may also collect "non-personal information". We consider "non-personal information" to be information that, by itself, cannot be used to identify you personally, such as demographic information (your age, gender, income, education, profession, area code, zip code, etc.). Non-personal information includes information that you include in your profile or contribute as user submissions for presentation on the Websites, and may also include technical information, such as your IP address, the type of browser you are using, the websites you visit immediately before and immediately after you visit the Websites, other anonymous data involving your use of the Websites, and other information that you provide us through your use of the Websites such as the terms you enter into the search functions of the Websites. You may also use the privacy settings on your account to control the availability of your information to other Users.

C. Cookies – We use "cookies" to enhance your visits to the Websites. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies do not store personal information about you, unless you knowingly provide it. Cookies can store non-personal information, such as what websites, pages, or advertisements your browser has accessed. We use cookies to store information and personalize your experience with the Websites. For example, cookies allow the Websites to recognize your browser as a previous visitor, and thus save and remember any preferences that may have been set while you were previously browsing the Websites. Our cookies can also store your password, personalize pages, and keep track of any selections you may make.

You do have control over cookies. Most browsers can be set to notify you when a cookie is being placed on your computer. Most browsers can also be set to refuse to accept cookies, although this may affect your Internet experience. You can also erase cookies that are already on your computer. For more information about working with cookies, you should consult your user manual, FAQ, or "help" function of your specific browser and operating system software.

D. Web Beacons – We also may use "web beacons" (also often referenced as "clear GIFs", "clear pixels", "1×1 GIFs", or "1×1 pixels") which are tiny graphic image files, embedded in a web page in GIF, jpeg or HTML format, that provide a presence on the web page and send back to its home server information from your browser, such as the IP address, the URL of the page on which the web beacon is located, the type of browser that is accessing the site and the ID number of any cookies on your computer previously placed by that server. We may use web beacons to collect non-personal information about your use of the Websites and the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using the Websites and selected sponsors' and advertisers' sites. Our web beacons are not used to track your activity outside of the Websites or those of our sponsors. We do not link non-personal information from web beacons to personally identifiable information without your permission.

E. Modification and Deletion – Users of the Websites may modify or delete any of their personal information, Profile information or User Submissions at any time by logging into their account. Information will be updated immediately. Individuals who wish to deactivate their account may do so. Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to other Users.

Where you make use of the social networking and online education features of the Websites to share information with other individuals on the Websites (e.g., submitting a question or an answer to your Instructor, participating in discussions with other Users or submitting an entry to a Challenge), you generally cannot remove such communications.

2\. Use of Information We Collect

A. Our Services and Websites – We use your personal information to provide to you any services that you may request or require and to communicate with you and to allow you to provide User Submissions for posting on the Websites. We may also use your personal information to analyze how the Websites are being used and to improve the content of the Websites other Content which they offer. We may also share your personal information with our third-party business partners. We reserve the right to use, disclose, license, assign or otherwise transfer information which is not personal information (including User Submissions and Profiles) in any way we see fit.

B. Enforcement – We may use the information we collect in connection with your use of the Websites (including your personal information) in order to investigate, enforce, and apply our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy and Contest Rules.

3\. Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

A. Aggregate Information – Except as specifically set forth in this Policy, we do not share your personal information with any non-affiliated third party without your permission. We may disclose aggregate information, such as demographic information, and our statistical analyses to third parties, including advertisers or other business partners. This aggregate information does not include your personal information.

B. Affiliates and Non-Affiliates – We endeavor to restrict access to personal information to Schoolrunner's directors, officers, employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. We may, however, also share your personal information with certain websites that are controlled by us, or by entities under common control with us, so that they and we can offer you products and services that may be of interest to you.

C. Service Providers – We sometimes engage unaffiliated businesses to assist us in providing you certain services. For example, we may use third parties to provide advertising, marketing and promotional assistance, provide email services, or facilitate our online services. In those instances, we may need to share your personal information with them. We require these companies to use your personal information only to provide the particular product or service and do not authorize them to use your personal information for any other reason.

D. Business Transactions Involving Schoolrunner – As Schoolrunner continues to develop, we may buy other entities or business assets, or sell all or part of our business or assets, or combine with other businesses. If so, personal information as well as and non-personal information contained in Profiles and User Submissions that we have collected may be transferred as part of the transaction.

E. Other Disclosures – We may disclose personal information when we are required or requested to do so by law, court order or other government or law enforcement authority or regulatory agency; to enforce or apply our rights and agreements; or when we believe in good faith that disclosing this information is necessary or advisable, including, for example, to protect the rights, property, or safety of Schoolrunner, our users, or others.

YOU HEREBY ACKNOWLEDGE THAT SCHOOLRUNNER IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY INTERCEPTED INFORMATION SENT VIA THE INTERNET, AND YOU HEREBY RELEASE US FROM ANY AND ALL CLAIMS ARISING OUT OF OR RELATED TO THE USE OF INTERCEPTED INFORMATION IN ANY UNAUTHORIZED MANNER.

4\. Links

The Websites may contain links to other websites. We have no control over the privacy practices or the content of any of our business partners, advertisers, sponsors or other websites to which we provide links from the Websites. You should check the applicable privacy policy of the website sponsor when linking to other websites.

5\. Security of the Information We Collect

The security of your personal information is important to us. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to secure your personal information. However, there is always some risk in transmitting information electronically. The personal information we collect is stored by us or by our third-party designees within databases that we or our third-party designees control. As we deem appropriate, we use security measures consistent with industry standards, such as firewalls and encryption technology, to protect your information. However, we cannot guarantee the security of our or our third-party designees' databases, nor can we guarantee that information you supply won't be intercepted while being transmitted to us or our third-party designees over the Internet or that information we share with others as permitted by this Policy will always be held secure by them.

6\. Accuracy of the Information We Collect

Any questions you may have regarding this Policy, the accuracy of your personal information or the use of your personal information, or any requests that we correct, update, or remove your information in our databases, should be directed via our contact form.

After receiving a request to change your information, we will make reasonable efforts to ensure that all of your personal information stored in databases we actively use to operate the Websites will be updated, corrected, changed or deleted, as appropriate, as soon as reasonably practicable. However, we reserve the right to retain in our archival files any information we remove from or change in our active website databases. We may retain such information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our terms and conditions of use. In addition, it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to us. A copy of your personal information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate.

7\. Your California Privacy Rights

Under Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information with respect to the types of personal information the business shares with third parties for those third parties' direct marketing purposes, and the identities of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. To exercise your rights, you may make one request each year by our contact form with "Request for California Privacy Information" on the subject line and in the body of your message. Be sure to provide in the request sufficient information to properly identify you and/or the members of your family.

8\. Changes in Policy

We reserve the right to change this Policy at any time, and will post any changes to this Policy as soon as they go into effect. You are bound by any minor changes to the policy when you use the Websites after those changes have been posted. Please refer back to this Policy on a regular basis. If, however, we are going to use Users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify Users by posting a notice on the Websites for 30 days.

9\. What If You Do Not Agree to the Terms of This Privacy Policy?

As a registered User of the Websites, or otherwise by using the Websites, you signify that you agree to this Policy. If you do not agree to this Policy, please do not make any use of the Websites.

This Privacy Policy was last revised on March 31, 2015. We welcome your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at [hello@schoolrunner.org](mailto:hello@schoolrunner.org).
